Have you ever been on social media and seen your favourite celebrity talking about a product?
你有没有在社交媒体上刷到过自己喜欢的名人推荐某款产品？
These endorsements might not be totally random, and are actually seen as a vital part of the marketing process.
这些代言并非完全是随机之举，实际上被视为营销过程中至关重要的一环。
The question is: How do social media influencers ‘influence’ what you buy?
问题来了：社交媒体网红究竟是如何“影响”你的购买决策的？
Human desire for status and making friends, combined with our need to belong to a group, make us susceptible to being ‘socially influenced’.
人类对地位和交友的渴望，再加上我们渴望融入某个群体的需求，让我们很容易受到“社交影响”。
Companies often use that desire to have a similar lifestyle to a celebrity we admire to hawk or launch a product.
企业常常利用这种想要拥有心仪名人同款生活方式的心理，来兜售或推销某款产品。
So, what do these endorsements actually do?
那么，这些代言究竟能起到什么作用呢？
Firstly, they can be used to build brand awareness.
首先，代言可以用来提升品牌认知度。
A social media influencer should have a strong understanding of the platform they operate on, and therefore can create engaging content that not only adheres to the brand image, but sparks their followers’ interests in a product they might never have seen before.
社交媒体网红通常对自己运营的平台有着深刻的理解，因此能够创作出既有吸引力，又符合品牌形象的内容，同时还能激发粉丝对一款他们此前可能从未接触过的产品的兴趣。
Secondly, influencers can improve a company or product’s relationship with their customer base.
其次，网红能够改善企业或产品与客户群体之间的关系。
According to InMoment’s 2018 US Retail CX Trends Report on customer loyalty, 77% of buyers have been brand loyal for more than ten years. This is also true of 60% of millennials.
根据盈客洞察公司2018年发布的《美国零售客户体验趋势报告》中关于客户忠诚度的数据，77%的消费者对品牌的忠诚度可以维持十年以上，这一比例在千禧一代中也达到了60%。
A popular celebrity can target key demographics and talk or blog about a product, which can create an instant and lasting bond with the consumer.
一位人气名人能够精准定位核心消费群体，通过谈论或撰写博文推荐某款产品，与消费者建立起即时且持久的联结。
Lastly, influencers can improve customer buying habits with seemingly ‘unbiased opinions’.
最后，网红可以凭借看似“客观中立的观点”来影响消费者的购买习惯。
We are more likely to respond to ‘peer recommendation’ than traditional ads, meaning the fact we see an influencer as a ‘friend’ can make us less likely to be sceptical about what we are seeing.
相比传统广告，我们更容易接受“同辈推荐”，这意味着当我们把网红视作“朋友”时，就不太会对他们推荐的内容产生怀疑。
So, the next time you see a celebrity talking about a product, you might want to consider that this could be a carefully crafted marketing strategy designed to target your core needs.
所以下次当你再看到名人推荐产品时，不妨想一想，这或许是一个精心设计的营销策略，目的就是瞄准你的核心需求。
If you find yourself perusing a product you’ve seen on social media, you may well have been influenced.
如果你发现自己正在仔细浏览某款在社交媒体上刷到的产品，那么你很可能已经被影响了。